opencolleges.edu.au 2019-09-02

# PR1.4 Privacy and Personal Information Procedures Policy

 PR1.4 Privacy and Personal Information Procedures Policy
  Responsible Officer:           Chief Learning Officer
  Functional Owner:              Head of Product Marketing
  QAS Owner:                     Quality Manager
1. Background
    Open Colleges complies with all relevant Commonwealth, State and Territory legislation
    and regulatory requirements relevant to its operations, including the Australian Privacy
    Principles set out in the Privacy Act 1988.
2. Scope
    The scope of this policy includes:
          Collection and use of personal information
          Information collection via the OC website
          Disclosure of personal information
          Security and integrity of personal information
          Marketing
          Rights to access and correct records
          Complaints, questions or problems and contacting Open Colleges
          Publication
3. Compliance
    This policy and supporting documentation adheres to compliance with the following
    Standards for RTOs 2015:
    Standard Eight: The RTO cooperates with the VET Regulator and is legally compliant at
    all times: Clauses 8.1, 8.2, 8.5, 8.6
4. Definitions
     Australian Privacy Principles             13 Privacy principles for private sector organisations, Australian
     (APPs)                                    government, ACT government and Norfolk Island agencies covered
                                               by the Privacy Act 1988.
                                               https://www.oaic.gov.au/resources/agencies-and-
                                               organisations/training-resources/privacy-law-
                                               reform/AustralianPrivacyPrinciples_summary_v6.pdf
     Open Colleges Pty Ltd                     Identified as ‘we’, ‘us’ or ‘our’ in this document
     Personal information                      is information or an opinion, whether true or not, and whether
                                               recorded in a material form or not, about an identified
                                               individual or an individual who is reasonable identifiable.
5. Policy
    In the course of its business, Open Colleges Pty Ltd (Open Colleges, we, us, or our) may
    collect information from students or persons seeking to enrol with Open Colleges and
    other individuals who interact with Open Colleges in the course of its business, either
    electronically or in hard copy format, including information that personally identifies
    individual users. Open Colleges may also record various communications between
    individuals and Open Colleges.
 PR1.4 V3 Privacy Policy and Personal Information Procedures 10/03/17                                   Page 1 of 7

   In collecting personal information Open Colleges will comply with the requirements of the
   Australian Privacy Principles (APPs) set out in the Privacy Act 1988 (Cth) as amended by
   the Privacy Amendment (Enhancing Privacy Protection) Act 2012 (Privacy Act).
   From time to time, Open Colleges may be related to other entities (related entities) and
   this Privacy Policy applies if your personal information is dealt with by those related
   entities. A reference in this Privacy Policy to Open Colleges is also a reference to our
   related entities.
   5.1 Collection and use of personal information
        Personal information collected by Open Colleges may include (but is not limited to)
        the following:
         a. name;
         b. email address;
         c. contact details including telephone numbers (landline and mobile);
         d. education history;
         e. course and unit enrolment details; and
         f. information from your resume or job application if you apply for a job with us.
        Open Colleges will only collect personal information from individuals by fair and
        lawful means which is necessary for the functions of Open Colleges. Open Colleges
        will only collect sensitive information with the consent of the individual and if that
        information is reasonably necessary for the functions of Open Colleges.
        Open Colleges collects your contact information when you download a course
        brochure from our website. We collect your email address and phone number so that
        an Enrolment Consultant can get in touch with you.
        During an enrolment consultation, an Enrolment Consultant may collect additional
        information about you, such as work and education background and goals for the
        future, so that we can suggest possible courses for you in line with your future
        aspirations.
        The information requested from or otherwise collected about individuals by Open
        Colleges will only be used:
         a.   to provide details of study opportunities;
         b.   to enable efficient course administration;
         c.   to maintain proper academic records;
         d.   to report to government agencies as required by law;
         e.   to get in contact with you to provide you with a course consultation;
         f.   to provide updates about our products and services;
         g.   to carry out market data analysis so that we can continue to enhance our
              services and offering;
         h. to send you newsletters and promotions and to conduct online surveys and
              competitions;
         i. to communicate with you and provide you with information, products or services
              you have requested;
         j. to promote and market our products and services to you or provide you with
              information that we believe may be of interest to you;
         k. to personalise and customise your experiences on our website;
         l. to process any job application submitted by you;
         m. if you are an employee or other representative of a customer to which we provide
               our products and services or a supplier or service provider to us, to communicate
               with you about your or your employer's engagement with us;
PR1.4 V3 Privacy Policy and Personal Information Procedures 10/03/17                       Page 2 of 7

         n.   to share your personal information with our related entities and business
              partners; and
         o. as otherwise set out in this Privacy Policy.
        If an individual chooses not to give Open Colleges certain information, then Open
        Colleges may be unable to enrol that person in a course or supply them with
        appropriate information.
        When you enrol with us and become an Open Colleges Student, all information about
        you is retained securely in accordance with this Privacy Policy.
        Where we engage with you multiple times over a short period in relation to the same
        matter, we may not provide you with a separate notice about privacy each time we
        engage with you.
        You consent to us using your personal information in the above ways.
        We may collect and use your personal information for other purposes not listed
        above. If we do so, we will make it known to you at the time we collect or use your
        personal information.
        We do not otherwise collect, use or disclose your personal information without your
        permission, unless the collection, use or disclosure is:
         a.   in accordance with this Privacy Policy or any agreement you enter into with us;
         or
         b.   required or authorised by law, including without limitation the APPs under the
              Privacy Act.
   5.2 Information collected via our website
        5.2.1     Google Analytics
                   We use Google Analytics to help analyse how you use our website. Google
                   Analytics generates statistical and other information about website use by
                   means of cookies, which are stored on users' computers. The information
                   generated is used to create reports about the use of our websites. Google
                   will store this information. We will not (and will not allow any third party to)
                   use Google Analytics to track or to collect any personally identifiable
                   information of visitors to our websites. We will not associate any data
                   gathered from the websites with any personal information from any source as
                   part of our use of Google Analytics.
                   If you do not want your website visit data reported by Google Analytics, you
                   can install the Google Analytics opt-out browser add-on. For more details on
                   installing and uninstalling the add-on, please visit the Google Analytics opt-
                   out page at https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout
        5.2.2     Cookies
                   Like many websites, Open Colleges' websites may use 'cookies' from time to
                   time. Cookies are alphanumeric identifiers, which enables our systems to
                   recognise your browser and to automatically collect information such as your
                   IP address, operating system and browser type, for system administration.
                   This is statistical data about our user’s browsing actions and patterns and
                   does not identify any individual. We use this information to enhance the
                   content and services offered on our website.
                   You can configure your browser to accept all cookies, reject all cookies, or
                   notify you when a cookie is sent. Each browser is different, so check the
                   "Help" menu of your browser to learn how to change your cookie
                   preferences.
PR1.4 V3 Privacy Policy and Personal Information Procedures 10/03/17                         Page 3 of 7

                   If you disable the use of cookies on your web browser or remove or reject
                   specific cookies from our websites or linked sites then you may not be able to
                   gain access to all of the content and facilities in those websites.
        5.2.3     Web beacons
                   Web beacons are images that originate from a third party site to track visitor
                   activities. We use web beacons to track the visiting patterns of individuals
                   accessing our website.
        5.2.4     Third party content
                   Some of the content on our websites includes applications made available by
                   third parties, such as social media buttons or links that allow you to share
                   content or links to our websites through the relevant third party platforms.
                   These third party applications themselves may facilitate collection of
                   information by those third parties, through your interaction with the
                   applications and sometimes even if you do not interact directly with them.
                   We are not responsible for the technical operation of these applications or
                   the collection and use practices of the relevant third parties. Please visit the
                   relevant third party websites to understand their privacy practices and options
                   they may make available to you in relation to their collection of your personal
                   information.
   5.3 Disclosure of personal information
        Personal information about students studying with Open Colleges may be shared
        with the Australian Government and designated authorities, including the Australian
        Skills Quality Authority (ASQA), the Commonwealth Department with responsibility
        for administering the Higher Education Support Act 2003 (Cth), Higher Education
        Support Act 2003, the Tuition Assurance Scheme manager, National Centre for
        Vocational Education Research (NCVER) and organisations that run courses in
        conjunction with Open Colleges including other Registered Training Organisations
        (RTOs)
        This information includes personal and contact details, course and unit enrolment
        details and changes.
        Open Colleges may disclose, or provide access to, your personal information to third
        parties in connection with the purposes described in section 2 "Collection and use of
        personal information". Depending on the nature of your engagement with us, we may
        disclose your personal information to our related entities, to third parties that provide
        products and services to us or through us, or to other third parties (such as your
        referee(s) in connection with a job application you have submitted).
        We may also disclose your personal information to our website host or software
        application providers in certain limited circumstances, for example when our websites
        experience a technical problem or to ensure that they operate in an effective and
        secure manner.
        Open Colleges will not otherwise disclose an individual’s personal information to
        another person or organisation unless in accordance with this Privacy Policy.
        Any person or organisation that collects information on behalf of Open Colleges or to
        whom personal information is disclosed as described in this procedure will be
        required to not use or disclose the information for a purpose other than the purpose
        for which the information was collected by them or supplied to them.
        5.3.1     Overseas disclosures
                   Some of your personal information may be transferred, stored, processed or
                   used overseas by us or by third party service providers. This may happen if
                   our related entities are overseas, if we outsource certain activities overseas
PR1.4 V3 Privacy Policy and Personal Information Procedures 10/03/17                        Page 4 of 7

                   or if transactions, information, services or products have an overseas
                   connection. You consent to the collection, use, storage, and processing of
                   your personal information outside of Australia.
                   In particular, your personal information may be disclosed to third party
                   service providers which may store your personal information in the United
                   States of America and such other countries in which those parties or their, or
                   our, computer systems may be located from time to time, where it may be
                   used for the purposes described in this Privacy Policy, without us being
                   responsible under the Privacy Act for such use (or for any breach). In these
                   circumstances, you consent to the collection, use, storage and processing of
                   your Personal Information in those countries. Where such parties are located
                   overseas, you may have rights to enforce such parties' compliance with
                   applicable data protection laws, but you may not have recourse against those
                   parties under the Privacy Act 1988 (Cth) in relation to how those parties treat
                   your personal information.
   5.4 Security and integrity of personal information
        Open Colleges is committed to ensuring the confidentiality, security and integrity of
        the personal information it collects, uses and discloses.
        Open Colleges will take all reasonable steps to ensure that any personal information
        collected is relevant to the purpose for which is was collected, is accurate, up to date
        and complete.
        Open Colleges will store securely all records containing personal information and
        take all reasonable security measures to protect personal information it holds from
        misuse, interference, loss, unauthorised access, modification or disclosure.
        Where Open Colleges has no further use for personal information for any purpose
        disclosed by Open Colleges, or is no longer required to maintain that personal
        information (whichever is later), all reasonable steps will be taken to destroy or de-
        identify the information.
   5.5 Marketing
        You consent to us using your personal information for sending you information,
        including promotional material, about us or our products and services, as well as the
        products and services of our related entities and third parties, now and in the future.
        You also consent to us sending you such information by means of direct mail,
        telemarketing, email, SMS and MMS messages.
        If you do not want to receive marketing information from us, you can opt out from
        receiving such material in any of the following ways:
        a.    following the instructions in the relevant marketing communication;
        b.    clicking on the relevant 'Unsubscribe' link in a direct marketing email that you
              have received from us;
        c.    enrolled students can log into their account on our website and edit their
              communications preferences; or
        d.    contacting us using the contact details and specifying whether your request
              relates to opting out of a particular marketing channel or from all direct marketing
              communications from us.
   5.6 Right to access and correct records
        Individuals have the right to access or obtain a copy of the personal information that
        Open Colleges holds about them. Requests to access or obtain a copy of personal
        information must be made in writing. There is no charge for an individual to access
        personal information that Open Colleges holds about them; however Open Colleges
PR1.4 V3 Privacy Policy and Personal Information Procedures 10/03/17                      Page 5 of 7

        may charge a fee to make a copy. Individuals will be advised of how they may access
        or obtain a copy of their personal information and any applicable fees within 10 days
        of receiving their written request. Where it is reasonable to do so, access to the
        information will be provided in the manner requested by the individual.
        If an individual considers their personal information to be incorrect, incomplete, out of
        date or misleading, they can request that the information be amended. Where a
        record is found to be inaccurate, a correction will be made as soon as practical.
        Where an individual requests that a record be amended because it is inaccurate but
        the record is found to be accurate, the details of the request for amendment will be
        noted on the record. There is no charge for making a request to correct personal
        information.
        Written requests for access to, to obtain a copy of, or correct personal information
        held by Open Colleges should be sent to:
        Chief Learning Officer
        Open Colleges
        PO Box 1568
        Strawberry Hills NSW 2012
   5.7 Complaints, questions or problems and contacting Open Colleges
        If you:
        a.    have a query or concern about this Privacy Policy or our personal information
              handling processes; or
        b.    would like to opt out of direct marketing, please contact us at:
        Chief Learning Officer
        Open Colleges
        PO Box 1568
        Strawberry Hills NSW 2012
        If you wish to make a complaint:
        a.    students or prospective students may lodge a complaint using Open Colleges’
              Complaints Procedure (Document reference number PR 7.1) which will enable
              you to lodge complaints of a non-academic nature, including complaints about
              handling of personal information;
        b.    trainers and assessors may lodge a complaint in accordance with Open
              Colleges' Course Management Policy;
        c.    staff may lodge a complaint in accordance with our Human Resources Policies;
              and
        d.    for any other persons, complaints can be sent in writing to the Chief Learning
              Officer, Open Colleges, PO Box 1568, Strawberry Hills NSW 2012.
        Where not covered by a policy referred to above, we will investigate your queries and
        complaints within a reasonable period of time of receiving the complaint and will
        notify you of the outcome of our investigation.
   5.8 Publication
        This Privacy Policy and Personal Information Procedures will be made available to
        students and persons seeking to enrol with Open Colleges and other individuals who
        interact with Open Colleges by publication on Open Colleges’ website:
        www.opencolleges.edu.au. Alternatively, a copy of this Privacy Policy may be
        requested by contacting Open Colleges using the contact details provided above.
PR1.4 V3 Privacy Policy and Personal Information Procedures 10/03/17                    Page 6 of 7

          In order to ensure that students have given their informed consent for their personal
          information to be disclosed to certain third parties as outlined in this procedure, Open
          Colleges will advise students on enrolment about these procedures and where they
          are located.
6. Quality and Continuous Improvement
          This Policy and Procedure is subject to systematic review, evaluation and
          improvement, including annual review and ongoing feedback from stakeholders
7. Other related documents
          Our Education Blueprint V3, August 2013
8. Related Legislation and Guidelines
          Users’ Guide for Standards for Registered Training Organisations (RTOs) 2015
          Australian Privacy Principles
          Privacy Act 1988
 For internal use only: QMS1.8 Location of QMS related documents.
  Communication:
  All Policies, Procedures, Forms and Guidelines are loaded into the Quality Management System (QMS) in
  Open Colleges’ quality Space located in SharePoint. This will automatically update documents in all locations.
  Changes will be communicated to all staff via Firefly Chatter.
  Version:                       Approved               Endorsed            Effective date    Review date
                                 Chief Learning         Functional Owner
                3                Officer                                         10/03/17         10/03/18
                                                        10/03/17
                                 10/03/17
  Version History:               V1: September 2016 Created as part of the new format QMS documents. Content
                                 taken from PR1.1 V6 Pre-Enrolment Information Procedure and PR1.2 V9 Student
                                 Recruitment, Admissions & Enrolment Procedure
                                 V2: September 2016 – reformatted to new template
                                 V3: March 2017 – reformatted to new template
  Course Type:                   All
                                 Open Colleges Pty Ltd (90796)
  RTOs:                          Integrated Care and Management Training Pty Ltd (90197)
                                 College of Fashion Design (3798)
  Partner RTOs:                  Yes
 PR1.4 V3 Privacy Policy and Personal Information Procedures 10/03/17                                  Page 7 of 7
